<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-03-06T21:43:21+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dear Cover Letter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/dear-cover-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear Cover Letter" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/dear-cover-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/dear-cover-letter/"><![CDATA[<p>1st February 2023</p>

<p>Subject: Application to show some mercy</p>

<p>Dear Cover Letter,</p>

<p>With no excitement, I am writing to you to express my annoyance at you for constantly making me feel like a failure. Having completed my Master’s degree and gathered some skill sets along the way, I remain unemployed, and I thank you for it.</p>

<p>Every week, I come across new nuggets of information. ‘Your cover letter should not be longer than one page, but you should be able to tell an impressive story and stand out from hundreds of applicants.’ ‘Your cover letter should be quirky and fun.’ ‘Follow the standard cover letter format. Experimenting with it might backfire.’ ‘Customize your cover letter for each job application.’ ‘Do your research on each employer you are applying to. No! Going through their homepage does not count; you must go seven tabs deep and align your application to the info there. No! No one cares that you apply to multiple jobs every day, and your brain just breaks after a point.’ I am confused cover letter. I am so dizzy and so tired.</p>

<p>You are not the only one I am mad at, though. Your partner in crime CV/Resume does not help either. Yes, I still get confused between CV and resume, and I am unsure which one I have. I am tired of hearing things like, ‘Your CV should not be longer than one page. A recruiter looks at a CV only for seven seconds.’ ‘Some recruiters have the ATS software, which filters out CVs, so you need to have an ATS-friendly CV.’ And as if this was not excruciating enough, every vacancy will require a long form to be filled with customized answers. And the worst thing, you ask? Having to insert the information already in your CV to that customized form they have.</p>

<p>Well, before you say, I know it is not easy for recruiters. I am getting flashes of recruiters with long posts on LinkedIn explaining how difficult it is to get through hundreds of applications. So, I must reiterate; I am not taking away from their experiences. As a graduate applying to jobs almost every day for the past six months and not receiving any positive response (none whatsoever), it has not been fun on this side either.</p>

<p>Hence, I kindly request you to work in my favor for once. While this letter provides a glimpse into my annoyances, there is considerably more to share, and I look forward to ranting further.
Not looking forward to any more rejections.</p>

<p>Sincerely,</p>

<p>An average candidate seeking job in the current market</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1st February 2023]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Silver Lining</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/the-silver-lining/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Silver Lining" /><published>2023-01-15T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T18:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/the-silver-lining</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/the-silver-lining/"><![CDATA[<p>We often undermine the power of kindness. Even though I always tried to be kind to people around me, I did not realize the impact it could have on others until very recently. Just a kind gesture from a stranger or a small help from a colleague can make our day infinitely better.</p>

<p>The past eight months have been pretty difficult for me emotionally. I have been struggling to find a job (which is pretty much the whole theme of this website lol) and stressing over what my next steps could/should be. While I am going through this turmoil, there have been people who have made my life a little better. Many of them did not know even know that I was struggling. They were kind to me not out of sympathy but because that is who they are. They are just good people. I want to appreciate them here. I want to remind myself of how grateful I am to them.</p>

<p>While looking for a job related to my academic background, I joined a hostel as a housekeeper. I took the job because I needed the money. That was it. I did not give it any more thought. However, after working there for seven months now, I can say that the job went beyond just a way to make ends meet.</p>

<p>Housekeeping is a stressful job. There is too much to do and too little time on some days. It is very physical, and one has to work fast. I am not that fast, at least not as fast as some of my colleagues. Whenever I could not keep up despite trying my best, they were there to help. They never made me feel like I was at fault. Every colleague at the hostel has been nothing but kind through these months. They have treated me like their own. They have helped me whenever I needed them, always offered me whatever snack they had, and made me laugh countless times. The gestures might look small, but the hearts behind them were huge.</p>

<p>On the other hand, I am surprised and glad they could see me beyond my social awkwardness. I can get a bit reluctant to speak to new people, and this often comes out as me being rude. I believe they understood this side of me. We have sat in silence, on our phones, or just staring into the wall, and none of us felt the need to fill the silence.</p>

<p>Do not get me wrong. We talk and laugh. We make jokes too. It is just that we have been able to enjoy the comfort of silence too.</p>

<p>This experience only got better because of my supervisors at the hostel. The journey would not be this smooth if the supervisors had not been pleasant. I work mainly with two supervisors, both of whom are polar opposites. As cliché as it sounds, one of them is like a coconut. He looks serious from the outside and wants everything to be perfect. However he is always kind and supportive.</p>

<p>And the second supervisor is my favorite. Her presence at work makes my day better. To know that someone is there willing to take care of you is such a blessing. She is that person. She will always have a smile on her face and keeps an open mind. I can tell her about any problem at work, and she will be ready to help. What more could I ask for?</p>

<p>I have been lucky to find a workplace that has been a silver lining in my otherwise not-so-fun life. I wonder how difficult it would have been for me if I was stuck at a job I did not like and with people I could not connect to. I have probably not been able to directly express how grateful I am to all of them, but I am glad I am putting it down here at the least.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We often undermine the power of kindness. Even though I always tried to be kind to people around me, I did not realize the impact it could have on others until very recently. Just a kind gesture from a stranger or a small help from a colleague can make our day infinitely better.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Woman’s Day to Me- a learning, failing, growing woman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2021/happy-womens-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Woman’s Day to Me- a learning, failing, growing woman" /><published>2021-03-08T16:59:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-08T16:59:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2021/happy-womens-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2021/happy-womens-day/"><![CDATA[<p>Being a woman has been a fight- within me and with others. Is it similar for men too? Do men also second guess their choices every step of the way? Do men too imagine how they would react if someonw was to attack them while they were walking at night? Do men also get annoyed with family functions because it means a lot of time in the kitchen? Maybe they do. Maybe they do not. Well, I hope they do not have to, because, it’s not fun.</p>

<p>Anyways, I am here to write my own story today- the story of how I am struggling to understand what it means to be a woman. I have no idea when was the first time I heard about womanhood. I guess it is not a formal conversation in our homes- our mothers do not come to us and tell us ‘you are a woman, here is a set list of things you need to do. You will be punished if you do not follow them’. It is a much more subtle process than that. The idea is to indoctrinate it into you through socialization, to make you inherit this idea so that you cannot escape it. And mind you, you do get punished in many ways if you fail to comply.</p>

<p>For me, there are some instances that stand out from my life and I am going to talk about them here. When I was 12 or 13, I remember being told ‘why are you walking with your chest out? You need to be a little mellow and crouched. Cover the chest area. That’s how a woman should walk.’ I questioned it, challenged it, but when you get a death stare, you shut up and follow. So I thought ‘okay, that’s the correct way for me, a woman, to walk’ and I changed my posture that day.</p>

<p>Then came my first period. It was a hush-hush thing where my mother secretly gave me a sanitary napkin, hardly explained how to use it and it was a little secret among the women of the house. Hence, there was one more layer added to my ‘womanhood’- I understood that menstruation was a secret kept by all women and I was now part of this group.</p>

<p>When I was maybe 14, I was told ‘why do you laugh so much with your friends on your way home from school? Girls should not be laughing so much, they should be quieter.’ And Boom! Another layer! As a woman, I should be quiet and not laugh loudly. It irked me; I questioned why I was not allowed to laugh as much as I wanted? Wasn’t laughing a good thing? I was not given any explanation, just told that I needed to be a certain way. I agreed but I could not stop being myself. So, I still used to laugh with my friends but made sure I was mellow when family was around. I thought I was on my way to becoming the perfect woman, forgetting that I was losing who I actually was in the process.</p>

<p>One of those days, I remember, there was a small bridge on my way to school. There used to be guys sitting on that bridge and their sole aim was to pass lewd comments on women who walked by. I was an overweight adolescent girl, wearing all my insecurities on my sleeves. Every time I had to pass by the bridge, I used to pray that the guys were not there, but on many days, they were. And they made the usual comments about my weight and chuckled. I guess that too added a layer to my womanhood- I had to be ‘slim and beautiful’ to be respected. But, it irked me. I hated the fear that came all over me every time I was near that bridge. One day, I decided to carry some stones in my pocket thinking I would throw it at them if they said something. I genuinely do not remember if I did throw the stones- I probably did not as I did not have the guts to. But, I felt happy. I felt like I had finally done something to overcome my fear.</p>

<p>Sometime around this, a well meaning friend in my class had calmly explained to me ‘you are so smart and fun; only if you were ‘slim’, men would line up after you.’ As a 15 year old desperate for love and attention (not much has changed now either), I understood that a woman had to look a certain way to be loved by a romantic partner. Luckily, I did come across romantic partners, who saw me beyond my appearance, but those insecurities never went away completely (they still have not).</p>

<p>As the cherry on top, I was molested by a much older man one of these years and I did not know what happened was wrong back then. I used to sincerely greet ‘uncle’ every time I met him after that incident. Anyways, that’s a story for another day. The point is, I had now accepted that men were superior and I was there to fulfill their needs. You see how I am on my way to be a perfect woman?</p>

<p>But, none of this sat right with me. It irked me that it was always me who had to change, who had to accommodate others. I had to be pretty, I had to change my posture, I had to laugh less, I had to do this and that. My male friends were not given any such mandates. Were they? Even if they were, they can write about it on their own. This piece is about me, a woman, and my experiences.</p>

<p>Anyways, I started challenging the expected gender norms over time and still continue to do so. I went through a whole phase where I hated everything that was conventionally associated with women. I had read that women liked pink and played with dolls. I judged women who said their favorite color was pink. I think I trained myself to like black and blue. I did not like when I saw little girls playing with dolls, I wanted them to play with trucks and guns. I used to push my mother to buy blue unisex clothes as gifts for girl babies instead of frocks and dresses. I judged women who married young or became mothers early on. I thought being a homemaker was shameful. I thought my mother giving my father a glass of water after he comes back from long day at work was gender inequality. You can imagine how skewed my idea of womanhood and gender equality was.</p>

<p>Thankfully, I am evolving every day. It has been years of unlearning and relearning. It was been understanding that every woman has had different experiences that guide their decisions. It has been accepting that this is going to be a long process and I will never fully understand what womanhood is.</p>

<p>Womanhood has been a dichotomy for me. It has been me wallowing about the how unequal the world is towards me while I completely forget the privilege I have in comparison to many others. It is just me fighting with my mother about why girls cannot wear what they want but taking her and everything she does for us for granted. It is me hating to wear a bra and not wearing it but crouching when there are people around me so that no one figures it out. It is me being all vocal about my periods with people but still hiding it from my father. It is me hating on women who choose to be homemakers but sometimes imagining how ‘chill’ it would be to marry a rich husband and not worry about my career. It is me being a 25 year old woman living across the world from my family but still lying to them about little things. It is me pushing my sister to be strong and independent but never telling my brother to help out in the kitchen. It is me giving advice to other women about speaking up but freezing and not being able to say a word when a man presses his crotch against me on a bus. It is me attending seminars and conferences about gender equality but hoping that my partner takes me on a vacation. It is me wanting to challenge the expected gender norms but too scared to hurt the people I love by doing so. It is me judging fellow women for the choices they make without understanding their entire stories. It is me making decisions, some good and some bad, hoping to figure things out along the way.</p>

<p>Womanhood has been complex. I thought I would crack this phenomena but I have realized it is not a formula that can be solved. It is an experience. And might I say, it is quite challenging. But, I must reiterate, it is much more challenging for some other sections of the society. While I am allowed to complain of my own grievances, I must acknowledge the privilege I have, as a cis-gender straight woman from a fairly progressive middle class family. This journey of womanhood is much harder for many women around the world and I hope I will have the strength to empathize with them and always be an advocate for a more equal space for everyone.</p>

<p>To summarize this ramble, all I can say is that I am a woman- learning, failing and growing every day. And, a ‘Happy Women’s Day’ to me. May I always have the strength to fight for my independence and not fall into the gender expected roles when I don’t want to. May I have the strength to look past my imperfections, physically or otherwise, and respect myself. May I always acknowledge my privilege and never judge others for the decisions they make. May I never compromise on my ambitions and choose to depend on others just because it’s acceptable for a woman to do that. May I always push for ensuring deserving women to be in positions of power even when it is not me. May I get to see the world becoming a more equal place and play my small part in it. May I be able to learn and unlearn along the way and build a content life for myself.</p>

<p>Happy Women’s Day!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being a woman has been a fight- within me and with others. Is it similar for men too? Do men also second guess their choices every step of the way? Do men too imagine how they would react if someonw was to attack them while they were walking at night? Do men also get annoyed with family functions because it means a lot of time in the kitchen? Maybe they do. Maybe they do not. Well, I hope they do not have to, because, it’s not fun.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mainstream International Media turns a blind eye while Yemen suffers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/media-blind-yemen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mainstream International Media turns a blind eye while Yemen suffers" /><published>2020-08-17T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/media-blind-yemen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/media-blind-yemen/"><![CDATA[<p>While ‘media’ is hailed as the fourth pillar of the constitution and a completely impartial member of the civil society by idealists, the inherent bias in media’s approach and coverage is prominent, and even menacing, in today’s day and age. While the biggest democracies struggle by virtue of its notorious media’s extremist behavior, international media also seems to cater to specific ‘power-holders’ and only include as well as spread stories that suit their bias.</p>

<p>The unfair treatment of mainstream international media towards Yemen and its ongoing crisis clearly indicates the lack of objectivity and decreasing reliability in the media industry. Since the war broke out in 2015, Yemen is going through an extreme humanitarian crisis	 and millions of citizens are living in horror. About 100,000 people have lost their lives to this war while 8.4 million people are food insecure. https://www.mironline.ca/the-silent-war-how-the-u-s-media-failed-yemen/  In a report published by UNICEF in 2017, it was stated that a child dies every 10 minutes in Yemen and 400,000 Yemeni children are at a risk of starvation https://www.dw.com/en/yemen-conflict-all-but-ignored-by-the-west/a-37157913.</p>

<p>Saudi Coalition (United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Oman, Kuwait and Bahrain), also known as the PGCC (Persian Gulf Cooperation Council) has left no stone unturned to ensure that Yemeni citizens live a horrifying life and struggle to even have a basic hand-to-mouth existence. Since the Houthi rebel group ousted then President Abdrabbuh Mansour Hadi in 2015, it seems like PGCC is determined to reinstall the former government in Yemen and is taking extreme measures for it. They have imposed a blockade on Yemen which has left 20 million people in need of humanitarian assistance while more than 12,000 people have lost their lives to this selfish act. https://www.tehrantimes.com/news/422166/Three-years-of-Saudi-heinous-crimes-in-Yemen</p>

<p>While Yemen suffers, rest of the world has almost turned a blind eye to it, likely because of the power dynamics that exists among states. Yemen is getting ‘weaker’ by the day and Saudi coalition is the new favorite in town- hence, despite the severity of these circumstances, the news is often not picked by many mainstream media houses barring a few. It is believed that Iran, a political foe to Saudi, is backing the Houthi rebel group while Saudi is backing the former government. Hence, many argue that, whenever the news is covered, it is driven by the narrative of Saudi v/s Iran and completely ignores the ongoing crisis in Yemen. https://www.dw.com/en/yemen-conflict-all-but-ignored-by-the-west/a-37157913</p>

<p>The local journalists in Yemen, who are observing and living the crisis everyday, are also compelled to not report any of it because of the danger surrounding it. The Yemeni Journalist Syndicate reports that more than a 100 press violations were committed in the first few months of 2016 itself whereas there have been multiple cases of abductions and assaults targeted to journalists. https://www.dw.com/en/yemen-conflict-all-but-ignored-by-the-west/a-37157913 Thus, it is almost impossible for local journalists to find a safe space to cover the news in Yemen and foreign journalists have also basically decided to not cover it. That is one of the reasons behind this war being termed the ‘forgotten war’. https://www.trtworld.com/opinion/media-has-completely-failed-to-hold-anyone-accountable-for-yemen-misery-25303</p>

<p>Even when International media does cover the happenings of Yemen, it is often presented as a Saudi-Iranian war and almost always ‘forgets’ to mention the role of western governments in fuelling the war. It is known that Saudi gets most of its arms and ammunitions from UK, US and France and Saudi even uses the satellite technology from US to identify targets during air strikes. It is reported that the US had sold $5.5 billion and UK had sold $1.4 billion worth of arms and ammunitions to the Saudi coalition by the end of 2017. https://www.trtworld.com/opinion/media-has-completely-failed-to-hold-anyone-accountable-for-yemen-misery-25303</p>

<p>This clearly explains the conflict of interest that International media faces while covering the news. The western media, who boast about their democratic and impartial approach, have deprived their audience of the harsh realities of Yemen and kept it all under the wraps. The realities of the war in Yemen is covered so rarely in the media that people hardly get enough information to get interested or understand the issue and raise their voices against it. As a professor at the University of Sheffied, Piers Robinson told Al Jazeera ‘”When you have coverage which doesn’t really provide context or a proper understanding of the key actors in a conflict and also the role of our own governments, publics are left with a sense of a confused conflict where it’s not clear who’s right or wrong, it’s not clear whether or not we’re involved in it”. It all seems like a systematic plan- power holders do as they please and the ones who are supposed to question their intentions and actions choose to just not see the problem.</p>

<p>Along with mainstream international media’s own bias, another major factor hindering the coverage of news on Yemen is the danger associated with it. Even if a independent journalist does want to visit and report from Yemen, there is a lot of danger involved that makes them pull back. Afrah Nasser, an independent Yemeni Journalist based in Sweden talked to DW about ‘parachute journalism’. He explained that the coverage by international media is not very detailed as it is actually difficult to access Yemen easily. Entering in the country and then coming back is a lot of hassle which might not be preferable to many. https://www.dw.com/en/yemen-conflict-all-but-ignored-by-the-west/a-37157913 One of the other reasons behind this lack of coverage is Saudi Arabia strategy of buying media silence and hiring many PR companies to polish its image.</p>

<p>Whatever the reasons might be, the ultimate truth remains that Yemen is suffering and it needs strong voices to speak for it and support it. And for that to happen, people must have access to information regarding the ongoing crisis in Yemen so that they can take a stand. Thus, mainstream media must let go of their bias, keep the politics and power dynamics aside, and be as objective as possible to ensure that everyone has access to reliable information.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While ‘media’ is hailed as the fourth pillar of the constitution and a completely impartial member of the civil society by idealists, the inherent bias in media’s approach and coverage is prominent, and even menacing, in today’s day and age. While the biggest democracies struggle by virtue of its notorious media’s extremist behavior, international media also seems to cater to specific ‘power-holders’ and only include as well as spread stories that suit their bias.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Selfish Approach towards Handling a Pandemic- NATO continues with its war drills and US turns a blind eye to the social crisis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/nato-war-drills/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Selfish Approach towards Handling a Pandemic- NATO continues with its war drills and US turns a blind eye to the social crisis" /><published>2020-07-20T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-20T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/nato-war-drills</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/nato-war-drills/"><![CDATA[<p>Even when there is a pandemic around that has infected millions of people and taken many lives, countries still seem to be distracted and involved in activities that might not be of a priority at present. Instead of focusing its time and resources to fight the COVID-19 pandemic, many economies are diverting their energy towards things that are not as urgent. One such (almost) irresponsible task was carried out by NATO- as they carried out war drills/military exercise in the Baltic Sea recently.</p>

<p>NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organization) is an intergovernmental military alliance between 30 countries from North America and Europe. This alliance started in 1949 after the participating countries signed the North Atlantic Treaty. NATO conducts these military exercises, called BALTOPS, in the Baltic Sea almost every year whereby troops from different countries participate and practice their war mechanisms. The exercise was carried out from 7th June 2020 to 16th June 2020 this year, in which, around 3000 personnel from 19 different NATO members participated. BALTOPS is the largest military exercise carried out in the Baltic Sea and was carried out with around 30 ships and submarines and 30 aircrafts this year.</p>

<p>It was stated that certain precautions were taken to prevent the spread of COVID-19 among the participating personnel. All the personnel were tested for COVID-19 before the operations began. The exercise was commanded by the Naval Striking and Support Forces (NATO/STRIKFORNATO) from its headquarters offshore in Lisbon, Portugal instead of being present at the site. They had also reduced the number of personnel participating in the exercise to minimize the ‘crowd’. Similarly, no amphibious drills were used in the exercise to make sure that there is no spreading of the virus between the ships and land. The entire exercise was conducted in the sea. Officials also informed that the personnel were asked to maintain a safe distance and practice social distancing during the exercise.</p>

<p>Many have criticized these precautions stating that this military exercise was conducted at high risk and the measures taken were not enough. It is almost impossible for participants to maintain a safe distance during such an intense exercise and thus, it can be said that they were in risk of getting infected.  Julian Pawlak and Sebastian Bruns, two naval analysts at the University of Kiel expressed that even though the scope of the exercise was reduced, the fact that it was still organized in the middle of a pandemic indicated an attempt to project power play and strength by participating countries. The BALTOPS operations were also condemned this year because they were carried out despite Russia proposing against it. Russia shares its border with the Baltic Sea, hence, even when Russia proposed to not carry out the operations because of the pandemic, NATO declined their proposal and went forward with it.</p>

<p>While the pandemic is impacting the lives of millions of people, some of the most developed countries still seem to not completely understand, accept and realize the gravity of this situation. One of the most talked about countries right now is the United States, also a leading member of NATO, as it has been criticized constantly for taking the pandemic lightly and thus exposing its people to this deadly virus. Donald Trump’s response to this virus has almost been predictable- he continues boasting about himself, believes that he has handled the crisis well and refuses to see the errors in his approach. This attitude of the president seems to reflect on the citizens too as there is a lot of negligence on their behalf as well. While many U.S. residents understand the seriousness of the situation and advocate for the precautionary measures, significant number of people continue fighting for their right to ‘individual freedom’ and in turn refuse to do even the bare minimum to minimize the risk, that is, wear a mask. It is safe to say that American society is in a social crisis now and it struggles to unite, to fight possibly the biggest threat of our generation. It is a classic example of a ‘frog in the well’situation as many people have turned a blind eye to the risks in the bigger picture while basking in the glory of their ‘privilege’.</p>

<p>Yascha Mounk of ‘The Atlantic’ identifies various theories to explain the irresponsible behavior of US residents. According to him, the simplest explanation is ignorance. Some U.S. residents are genuinely ignorant and haven’t followed the news properly to understand the seriousness of the situation. This sounds unrealistic as COVID-19 is being discussed everywhere at all times and it is almost impossible to avoid information about it. Mounk’s second explanation is that people are being straightaway selfish. Some people do not care about the risk and the adverse effects of the virus and thus, they continue to lead their lives like they did before. Based on what is floating on the internet, this explanation seems much more likely as certain people in the U.S. seem to have completely disregarded the risk associated with the virus. This behavior is ‘immoral’ as people, in the name of their ‘individual rights’ are willing to harm the society, which is unjustifiable and unacceptable.</p>

<p>Whatever the reason might be, it is safe to say that the social crisis in America right now is at its worst. From the mishandling of the pandemic by the state to the reckless behavior of many of its citizens, U.S. has become the most affected country by the pandemic and struggles to find a way out of it despite being one of the strongest economies in the world.</p>

<p>References used:</p>

<p>https://www.militarytimes.com/news/your-military/2020/06/11 russia-nato-conduct-parallel-wargames-over-baltic-sea/
https://www.nato.int/cps/en/natohq/news_176191.htm#:~:text=Around%203%2C000%20personnel%20from%2019,and%20submarines%2C%20and%2030%20aircraft.
https://www.defensenews.com/global/europe/2020/06/04/warships-mass-in-the-baltic-sea-for-a-coronavirus-conscious-battle-drill/
https://valdaiclub.com/a/highlights/-defenders-of-europe-threats-to-the-world-or-why/
https://www.lrt.lt/en/news-in-english/19/1186728/nato-kicks-off-baltic-sea-drills-downscaled-due-to-pandemic
https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-52012049
https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/03/moral-instincts-coronavirus/608305/</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even when there is a pandemic around that has infected millions of people and taken many lives, countries still seem to be distracted and involved in activities that might not be of a priority at present. Instead of focusing its time and resources to fight the COVID-19 pandemic, many economies are diverting their energy towards things that are not as urgent. One such (almost) irresponsible task was carried out by NATO- as they carried out war drills/military exercise in the Baltic Sea recently.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">China’s Growing Footprint Over Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/china-expansion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China’s Growing Footprint Over Nepal" /><published>2020-06-09T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/china-expansion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2020/china-expansion/"><![CDATA[<p>A geographically small nation surrounded by two huge economies- China and India, Nepal has had an interesting experience interacting with its neighbors over the years. While India is the moody neighbor who Nepal has shared a love-hate relationship with for decades, China is the silent neighbor, almost menacing, who was always present but has recently become a lot more closer to Nepal.</p>

<p>Nepal has become an important venue for both the countries, primarily because of the massive unexplored resources and potential that this geographically small and landlocked country has to offer. And, with the increasing friction between Nepal and India over various issues, China has suddenly become much closer to Nepal and is almost considered a ‘savior’ to Nepal by some, whereas others see a real threat in this regard.</p>

<p>To delve into the history of China and Nepal’s bilateral relation, it started back in 1960 when both the countries signed the ‘Sino-Nepal Treaty of Peace and Friendship.’ After being cordial (but not engaging too much) for many decades, China and Nepal have become much more active and involved with each other in recent times. China’s involvement in Nepal’s internal affairs started increasing after the abolition of monarchy in 2008 but the change in this relationship was defined by the events of 2015, when Nepal and India had disputes over a variety of issues and Nepal turned to China for help. While India had imposed an unofficial economic blockade on Nepal, China stepped up and supported the import of goods for Nepal through their channel making them a strong ally to Nepal in testing times.
In 2015, the two major communist parties of Nepal formed a coalition government and this government, in March 2016, signed a historic ‘trade and transit agreement’ with China. This treaty aimed to end the dependence of Nepal on India for its supply chains and instead switch to China. According to this treaty, Nepal would use the dry ports as well as sea ports of China for trade of goods and China would invest in various sectors in Nepal. The principle behind this treaty was criticized by experts as it gave China access to much more of Nepal’s resources and created more tension between India and Nepal.</p>

<p>China’s interest and influence on Nepal was clearly visible when the coalition government was having some internal issues after a few months of signing the treaty. China expressed dissatisfaction on the crack that had occurred in the communist coalition government of Nepal and hinted that it did not want the government to fall. A newspaper in China published an editorial about how Nepal’s Prime Minister should not resign and if done so, there will be an increased uncertainty on China’s interest in investing in Nepal. Many viewed this as a subtle ‘threat’ by China in order to ensure that the communist government remains intact.</p>

<p>The Chinese government has developed close ties with the communist parties and is believed to intervene in the internal decisions of these parties. China pushed the two major communist parties- the CPN (Maoist Center) and CPN- Unified Marxist-Leninist (CPN-UML) to come together and form a single party. The parties finally unified in March 2018 and China’s influence has only gotten stronger ever since.</p>

<p>Another event that really pushed the diplomatic relationship between the two economies was Nepal’s decision to support China’s Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) and formally sign the initiative in 2017. China was actively looking to bring all its neighboring countries on board and Nepal’s instant support was a positive blow in that regard. But, this particular decision was also criticized by many in Nepal as it was believed that this decision was taken rather hastily and without considering the implications. Similarly, during his visit to Nepal in 2019, Chinese President Xi Jingping pledged $500 million in financial aid to Nepal. Twenty deals were signed by both the leaders which included issues of connectivity, security ties and trade.</p>

<p>The biggest threat of China investing in Nepal can be explained with one simple concept; Debt-trap diplomacy.  Debt-trap diplomacy is a term that was specifically coined to explain the foreign lending practices of China. In this practice, the creditor country (China) lends excessive amount of credit to the debtor country (mostly developing/underdeveloped economies) with the intention of extracting various political and economic gains when the debtor country is unable to pay back and is obliged to bow down to the creditor and honor the debt obligations. Sri Lanka, Laos and other economies have fell into this trap and had to suffer major economic downfall. Nepal is also at a high risk of facing something similar or even worse that might lead the entire economy to collapse. It is too soon now to clearly identify if something of that sort is happening as the aid was pledged fairly recently but there are various other aspects where China’s footprint can be seen growing by the day.</p>

<p>Nepal has showed its support to ‘One China Policy’ and has increased surveillance in the northern districts of the country to track the inflow of Tibetan refugees so that they can be deported immediately. This indicates an interesting turn of events as Nepal has been known to host as much as 20,000 Tibetan refugees every year in the past. The refugees and even the locals have questioned the government for suddenly changing their stance and doing everything to ‘please’ China.</p>

<p>China has also managed to have its mark in the ‘religion’ and ‘culture’ aspects of Nepal with increased investment in Lumbini (birth place of Buddha) and the surrounding area. It almost seems like, with every investment, China is getting an upper hand and controlling a lot of decisions. All the hydropower projects in Nepal that are funded by China have Chinese engineers and workers employed in it and many crucial decisions are hence taken by the Chinese authorities. This has made Nepal take a backseat in its own major projects which is definitely not a good sign in the long run.</p>

<p>In a world defined by ‘Globalization’, it is not unnatural for economies to come together and support each other. What is extremely important though, is that countries do not compromise on their sovereignty and ensure that the ties they make are beneficial in the long run. For Nepal as well, this transformed relationship with China has opened a lot of new possibilities and avenues and it must try to explore them as much as possible. But, having said that, Nepal must not agree to every offer China makes just because it looks tempting on the outside. Nepal must understand the implications of every association with China and act in a diplomatic yet cautious way.</p>

<p>It must also be realized that a ‘bilateral’ relationship, by definition, means a relationship that affects two parties whereby one party cannot dominate the other- despite the size of their economy or the power they hold. Thus, Nepal too must set clear boundaries and strive to strike a balance with regard to how it interacts with China or India or any other economy per se.</p>

<p>References used:
https://www.trtworld.com/opinion/china-s-silent-foray-into-nepal-30727
https://thediplomat.com/2020/05/chinas-growing-political-clout-in-nepal/
https://thediplomat.com/2019/10/from-land-locked-to-land-linked-chinas-xi-goes-to-nepal/
https://www.orfonline.org/research/chinas-growing-footprint-in-nepal-challenges-and-opportunities-for-india/
https://www.dw.com/en/nepals-delicate-balancing-act-between-china-and-india/a-52693835
https://www.orfonline.org/expert-speak/chinese-president-xi-jinpings-visit-to-nepal-is-it-a-diplomatic-victory-for-china-56821/</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A geographically small nation surrounded by two huge economies- China and India, Nepal has had an interesting experience interacting with its neighbors over the years. While India is the moody neighbor who Nepal has shared a love-hate relationship with for decades, China is the silent neighbor, almost menacing, who was always present but has recently become a lot more closer to Nepal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chhaupadi Pratha:Till When?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2016/chhaupadi-pratha/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chhaupadi Pratha:Till When?" /><published>2016-06-10T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-10T19:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2016/chhaupadi-pratha</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2016/chhaupadi-pratha/"><![CDATA[<p>There is this small mud hut outside many homes in Bajura district in Nepal.Temporarily made, dirty, unmanaged and just big enough to fit one person in, this hut is where women are forced to live every time they menstruate.</p>

<p>These girls/women isolate themselves from everything around them and stay inside the hut for 5-8 days every month just to avoid ‘polluting’ their surrounding with their ‘sin.’</p>

<p>Chhaupadi Pratha sounds like a horror story for those of us who don’t have to follow the tradition, but it’s a harsh reality for women in western Nepal. Its prevalence has no valid argument or scientific reason but still has been in practice for long enough to have affected countless women physically, sexually, and emotionally.</p>

<p>Young girls who menstruate for the first time are instructed to stay away from their family members and live isolated for as long as 22 days. They are not only forbidden to do regular activities and live together with their families, but prohibited to even look at male members of their family. And this doesn’t stop at the end of their first period. They are required to abide by the same set of restrictions everytime theyr menstruate (for 4-7 days). If a menstruating woman touches anything she isn’t supposed to, a thorough purification ritual is conducted.</p>

<p>There are a lot of myths surrounding this custom. In many cases, menstruating females are not allowed to touch bottled pickles as it is believed that their touch will decay it. They are asked to stay away from trees because it is believed that they will stop bearing fruits once touched by an ‘impure’ woman. Furthermore, instead of providing women on their periods with nutritious food, there are restrictions in what they can and cannot eat. For example, in many communities, they have to eat meals devoid of salt. It goes without saying that they aren’t allowed to enter temples, or kitchen.</p>

<p>While living in those congested mud huts, issues of hygiene and sanitation are completely neglected. The idea of sanitary napkins is far beyond their accessibility. Lack of nutritious food often weakens them physically. The trauma and stress of being mindful about not ‘polluting’ something by their touch and living isolated often lead to deep emotional scars. A condition called ‘conversion disorder’ is diagnosed in many females of western Nepal nowadays. They feel sick, weak and suffocated and the cause behind this is related to menstruation. While reports of animal attacks causing injuries to menstruating women living in the secluded sheds are common, cases of rapes and sexual violence are frequently on the news.</p>

<p>Why this barbaric practice? Often the answer is summed up in two words— culture and tradition. Why is it so easy to do something as radical as this in the name of culture? The acceptance of this custom by people, especially females themselves, is evidence to how deep-rooted this tradition is. The taboos related with menstruation have been practiced for so long that pamphlets or plays cannot do much to alter people’s beliefs.</p>

<p>Although the supreme court of Nepal banned this practice back in 2004-2005, it is still highly prevalent. Some families might have started using cow sheds instead of little mud huts, or confined their menstruating female member to a room in their own house, but Chhaupadi is still very much practiced.</p>

<p>The practice of confinement during child birth is also another form of Chhaupadi. As soon as a woman is in labor, she cannot be touched by anyone and has to give birth to the child all by herself (while delivery occurs at home). If that was not enough, she is the one who has to clean herself and her child within hours of child birth. She is then isolated for up to 11 days until the religious naming ceremony of the child. The new mother isn’t allowed to consume any salt, either.</p>

<p>I was told a heartbreaking incident about a woman who lost her child during childbirth. As no one would touch her or the child, she had to bury the child herself. She then visited the grave and dug the earth every day to see her child. This continued for a few days before she finally died of grief.</p>

<p>The scenario has been changing by virtue of time and efforts. The Chhaupadi sheds are now being removed from many families and communities. Women are raising their voices against the practice. The constant efforts of different organizations working to generate awareness against this practice have compelled people to question the logic behind this practice.</p>

<p>Treating women as untouchables during a natural cycle is nothing but ignorance. While we brag about our country being in a new phase and the new constitution bringing new dawn, I can only hope that women and their issues are included in the conversation as we build a stronger tomorrow together.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is this small mud hut outside many homes in Bajura district in Nepal.Temporarily made, dirty, unmanaged and just big enough to fit one person in, this hut is where women are forced to live every time they menstruate.]]></summary></entry></feed>