<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-02-12T22:39:05+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Oh! My Delusions,</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/oh-my-delusions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh! My Delusions," /><published>2023-02-07T16:59:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-07T16:59:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/oh-my-delusions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/oh-my-delusions/"><![CDATA[<p>Want to hear something funny?</p>

<p>Until December 2020, I thought moving to Norway will change my life.</p>

<p>Until April 2021, I thought I was smart.</p>

<p>Until June 2021, I thought I was good at physical work.</p>

<p>Until October 2021, I thought I will be financially stable soon.</p>

<p>Until December 2021, I thought I will have a job by the time I graduate.</p>

<p>Until March 2022, I thought I was a strong independent woman.</p>

<p>Until July 2022, I thought I had some potential.</p>

<p>Until October 2022, I thought I will figure something out.</p>

<p>In February 2023, all I am is a moody lump of flesh.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to hear something funny?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dear Cover Letter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/dear-cover-letter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear Cover Letter" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/dear-cover-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/dear-cover-letter/"><![CDATA[<p>1st February 2023</p>

<p>Subject: Application to show some mercy</p>

<p>Dear Cover Letter,</p>

<p>With no excitement, I am writing to you to express my annoyance at you for constantly making me feel like a failure. Having completed my Master’s degree and gathered some skill sets along the way, I remain unemployed, and I thank you for it.</p>

<p>Every week, I come across new nuggets of information. ‘Your cover letter should not be longer than one page, but you should be able to tell an impressive story and stand out from hundreds of applicants.’ ‘Your cover letter should be quirky and fun.’ ‘Follow the standard cover letter format. Experimenting with it might backfire.’ ‘Customize your cover letter for each job application.’ ‘Do your research on each employer you are applying to. No! Going through their homepage does not count; you must go seven tabs deep and align your application to the info there. No! No one cares that you apply to multiple jobs every day, and your brain just breaks after a point.’ I am confused cover letter. I am so dizzy and so tired.</p>

<p>You are not the only one I am mad at, though. Your partner in crime CV/Resume does not help either. Yes, I still get confused between CV and resume, and I am unsure which one I have. I am tired of hearing things like, ‘Your CV should not be longer than one page. A recruiter looks at a CV only for seven seconds.’ ‘Some recruiters have the ATS software, which filters out CVs, so you need to have an ATS-friendly CV.’ And as if this was not excruciating enough, every vacancy will require a long form to be filled with customized answers. And the worst thing, you ask? Having to insert the information already in your CV to that customized form they have.</p>

<p>Well, before you say, I know it is not easy for recruiters. I am getting flashes of recruiters with long posts on LinkedIn explaining how difficult it is to get through hundreds of applications. So, I must reiterate; I am not taking away from their experiences. As a graduate applying to jobs almost every day for the past six months and not receiving any positive response (none whatsoever), it has not been fun on this side either.</p>

<p>Hence, I kindly request you to work in my favor for once. While this letter provides a glimpse into my annoyances, there is considerably more to share, and I look forward to ranting further.
Not looking forward to any more rejections.</p>

<p>Sincerely,</p>

<p>An average candidate seeking job in the current market</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1st February 2023]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Silver Lining</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/the-silver-lining/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Silver Lining" /><published>2023-01-15T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T18:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/the-silver-lining</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2023/the-silver-lining/"><![CDATA[<p>We often undermine the power of kindness. Even though I always tried to be kind to people around me, I did not realize the impact it could have on others until very recently. Just a kind gesture from a stranger or a small help from a colleague can make our day infinitely better.</p>

<p>The past eight months have been pretty difficult for me emotionally. I have been struggling to find a job (which is pretty much the whole theme of this website lol) and stressing over what my next steps could/should be. While I am going through this turmoil, there have been people who have made my life a little better. Many of them did not know about my struggles or feelings either. They were kind to me not out of sympathy but because that is who they are. They are just good people. I want to appreciate them here. I want to remind myself of how grateful I am to them.</p>

<p>While looking for a job related to my academic background, I joined a hostel as a housekeeper. I took the job because I needed the money. That was it. I did not give it any more thought. However, after working there for seven months now, I can say that the job went beyond just a source of money. 
Housekeeping is a stressful job. There is too much to do and too little time on some days. It is very physical, and one has to work fast. I am not that fast, at least not as fast as some of my colleagues. Whenever I could not keep up despite trying my best, they were there to help. They never made me feel like I was at fault. Every colleague at the hostel has been nothing but kind through these months. They have treated me like their own. They have helped me whenever I needed them, always offered me whatever snack they had, and made me laugh countless times. The gestures might look small, but the hearts behind them were huge.</p>

<p>On the other hand, I am surprised and glad they could see me beyond my social awkwardness. I can get a bit reluctant to speak to new people, and this often comes out as me being rude. I believe they understood this side of me. We have sat in silence, on our phones or eating, or just staring into the wall, and none of us felt the need to fill the silence.</p>

<p>Do not get me wrong. We talk and laugh. We make jokes too. It is just that we have been able to enjoy the comfort of silence too.</p>

<p>This experience only got better because of my supervisors at the hostel. The journey would not be this smooth if the supervisors had not been pleasant. I work mainly with two supervisors, both of whom are polar opposites. As cliché as it sounds, one of them is like a coconut. He looks serious from the outside and wants everything to be perfect. However he is always kind and supportive.</p>

<p>And the second supervisor is my favorite. Her presence at work makes my day better. To know that someone is there willing to take care of you is such a blessing. She is that person. She will always have a smile on her face and keeps an open mind. I can tell her about any problem at work, and she will be ready to help. What more could I ask for?</p>

<p>I have been lucky to find a workplace that has been a silver lining in my otherwise not-so-fun life. I wonder how difficult it would have been for me if I was stuck at a job I did not like and with people I could not connect with. I have probably not been able to directly express how grateful I am to all of them, but I am glad I am putting it down here at the least.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We often undermine the power of kindness. Even though I always tried to be kind to people around me, I did not realize the impact it could have on others until very recently. Just a kind gesture from a stranger or a small help from a colleague can make our day infinitely better.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Well, on the personal front,</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2022/my-first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Well, on the personal front," /><published>2022-12-21T16:59:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-21T16:59:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2022/my-first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2022/my-first-post/"><![CDATA[<p>I am from Nepal. In case you are unaware, it is the land of Mount Everest. If you do not know what Mouth Everest is, it is the tallest mountain in the world. If you do not know what a mountain is, Google says it is a large elevation of the earth’s surface rising ‘abruptly’ from the surrounding level.</p>

<p>Okay! okay! okay! back to the point (as if there was any)- I moved to Norway over two years ago and Boy Oh Boy! it has been quite a ride. Being born and brought up in Nepal, Norway has been quite an interesting experience. The contrasts and similarities between both cultures are quite fascinating. However, my Norway stories deserve a separate piece so more on that later.</p>

<p>I come from a small town in Nepal. I was born and brought up in…</p>

<p>Okay, I am struggling to write this piece. My thoughts are all over the place. But guess what? My website, my rules so I will complete this later.</p>

<p>But, here are three things about me that are on top of my mind now:</p>

<ol>
  <li>I love love love my family.They mean everything to me.</li>
  <li>I am quite lazy.</li>
  <li>I dream too much.</li>
  <li>I like sharing stories- all kinds, all the time.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am from Nepal. In case you are unaware, it is the land of Mount Everest. If you do not know what Mouth Everest is, it is the tallest mountain in the world. If you do not know what a mountain is, Google says it is a large elevation of the earth’s surface rising ‘abruptly’ from the surrounding level.]]></summary></entry></feed>